(BELL TOLLING)
(BELL CONTINUES TOLLING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
WAITER: He said four minutes precisely.
POIROT: Non, non, non.
Quickly.
POIROT: (IN ENGLISH) Two perfect eggs this
time, no?
Ah.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
Hmm. Maybe.
I blame the chicken.
Why do hens lay eggs
of different sizes?
It's not you, mon ami.
These are two perfectly good oeufs. CHIEF
INSPECTOR: Mr.
Poirot...
I've got three religions bent on riot.
If you're going to perform one of your
miracles,
the time is now.
Have the eggs. Allons-y!
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(SQUELCH)
CHIEF INSPECTOR: Poirot!
Sorry for the, um...
It is not the, uh...
It is the imbalance of the...
CHIEF INSPECTOR: Right.
That's better.
(IN ENGLISH) Excuse me. Coming through.
Make way, please. Excuse me.
(CROWD CLAMORING)
Please call for the accused.
The rabbi...
the priest...
and the imam.
It is like the old joke, yes?
The rabbi, the priest, and the imam.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(IN ENGLISH) Forgive me, I am Belgian.
So, let us begin.
In the Church of the Holy Sepulchre above
us...
three representatives meet under the
supervision...
of the Chief Inspector of Police to
discuss a divided timetable
for market use.
One hour after this tense meeting...
a priceless relic is found to be stolen.
It is said, one of these three men has
stolen it.
The police find no pieces of evidence at
all.
I find one.
On the meticulously well-kept wall of a
fresco...
a single crack from an indelicate climb...
with a hard-soled shoe or perhaps a boot.
So, ladies and gentlemen, we must ask...
who stands to benefit from the crime.
Our three holy men live humbly.
They're thin-soled shoes poor.
Sudden riches and rubies would be... too
conspicuous, yes, to enjoy.
They do not gain.
At this point, we need an armed guard at
the south gate.
Thank you very much.
No, the only one...
who benefits from the theft and the unrest
it causes...
is a man whose office I had searched this
morning...
as I waited, I have to tell you,
rather disappointedly upon my breakfast.
Difficulty with eggs.
You don't need to know this.
A man who is paid lavishly to keep order
in Jerusalem.
I mean, of course,
the Chief Inspector of the Police.
A man who does not wish to lose a
well-paid post...
when there is discussion among the local
peoples
of self-governance...
who does wear boots, and who, I believe,
now does regret...
inviting me to consult on this case.
How dare you accuse me!
POIROT: Please, Sergeant...
did you search the office as I asked?
Uh, yes, sir.
And did you find what I said you might?
Just as you said.
Merci.
(GASPS)
(CROWD MURMURS) (CROWD CLAMORING)
(GUN COCKS)
Halt!
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
(MUMBLING INDISTINCTLY)
(BELL TOLLING IN DISTANCE) DELIVERY
GENERAL: You need
to deliver that, Captain.
It should be through first thing in the
morning.
DELIVERY GENERAL: Very good, sir.
Luggage is on board, sir.
I won the right to escort you to your
boat.
To Stamboul, then?
Will you be back to London straight off?
I am tired, and I have earned myself a
little holiday.
I want to look at paintings and have too
much time
on my hands.
You are staring.
Does it stop? It's just...
How did you know it was him, sir?
From just a tiny crack on the wall.
I have the advantage...
I can only see the world as it should be.
And when it is not, the imperfection
stands out...
like the nose in the middle of a face.
It makes most of life unbearable.
But it is useful in the detection of
crime.
But it's as though you see into their
hearts
and divine their true natures.
And whatever people say,
there is right, there is wrong.
There is nothing in between.
We must part here.
Oh, no, sir, I'm to escort you on the
ferry.
Au revoir, mon capitaine.
We must never meet again. Could you
straighten your tie, please?
Just a little.
Yes.
That is perfect.
(SHIP HORN BLOWING) MAN: Final passengers,
please!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MISS DEBENHAM: Oh, I'm sorry.
MAN 2: Will be fixed soon.
But, will it be fixed in time?
MAN 2: We are working!
I have a connection in Stamboul.
Leaves tomorrow at seven.
(HAMMERING) There's a very ill patient
waiting for me in London.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
I am a doctor.
DR. ARBUTHNOT: Doctor.
I am shouting at you in English, and now
I'm doing it
louder and slower.
Very silly, forgive me. (HAMMERING
CONTINUES) May I help?
Let me help.
I know your mustache.
From the papers.
You're the detective, Hercules Poirot?
Hercule Poirot. I do not slay the lions.
Mademoiselle. Mary Debenham, monsieur.
I'll forget a name but never a face.
Not yours, anyway.
You come from Baghdad?
It's true. No detail escapes his notice.
Your ticket.
Ah. I might also ask you if you enjoyed
your time there...
as a governess?
The chalk on your sleeve and the geography
primer.
A governess or a cartographer. I made my
gamble.
I always begin them with geography...
and monster them till they have the world
down cold.
They may get lost in life...
but I'll be damned if they don't know
where they are.
(WHISTLE BLOWING) (ENGINE WHIRRING)
Well, our chains are free. Right on time.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER) (GOAT BLEATING)
I feel so free out here on the water.
I wish I could enjoy it.
We should be out of this, Mary.
Not now.
When it's all over.
When it's done.
Then, nothing can touch us.
POIROT: Ah, my holiday begins here.
I can see the soul of the city in these
humble breads.
The world insists on destruction, yet
here...
masterpieces are baked to order every day.
(INHALES DEEPLY) BAKER: Monsieur Poirot!
Mohammed!
(LAUGHING) Mohammed, my friend...
you are an artist.
MOHAMMED: Ah! My friend!
Sorry.
Here.
Come, come. Don't mind us, we're just
looking
for a place to have a private argument.
It should take some 20 minutes or so...
at which point we will both come to an
agreement,
or at least I will.
Monsieur Bouc!
Poirot! In the kitchen?
Well, of course, this man will sniff out
a perfect pastry faster than he catches...
a jewel thief.
Mon ami!
Now, I am no longer a policeman.
I cannot bail you out when this goes
badly, eh?
(LAUGHING) This is my dear, old friend,
the esteemed...
Poirot, who I knew before the esteem.
Hercule Poirot, this is... A prostitute.
She is.
I am. Bouc, you did not tell me you had
famous friends.
BOUC: We're friends because I'm the only
person
who never asks him...
any questions about his cases, because I
don't care.
And he never judges me for being a
terrible person.
Indeed you are.
Madame, Bouc, please join me for a drink,
yes?
You only have me for an hour.
I ride on the Orient Express at seven,
official director business.
Uncle pays me absurdly to stay on board
his gorgeous train...
and far away from him...
at the home office...
consigned to wine and dine
handsome officials for all eternity.
There is an art to nepotism.
And you are its Michelangelo!
Mr. Poirot.
Are you a prostitute as well?
Certainly not.
Is this man bothering you?
POIROT: He is about to.
You are from the British consulate. I am,
sir.
It is the Kassner case.
Why, yes.
I was correct in certain predictions?
Quite.
I do not need to read the telegram.
BOUC: Oh, how fun.
Did someone cheat, or die?
POIROT: Unfortunately, both.
Someone has...
interrupted my longing for rest.
It appears that I must travel with you
tonight, Bouc.
Can you find me a cabin on the Orient
Express?
My friend...
I may not be good for much, but I sure as
hell
can get you a bed on my train... in the
dead of winter.
Three days...
free of care, concern or crime. You will
love it.
Mademoiselle, it has been a pleasure. Sir.
AYNESWORTH: Your luggage has been
collected
and your expenses paid.
You will be met at Calais...
and then escorted to Dover, and then by
rail
to London Victoria.
I would like to formally express
gratitude.
Please, don't speak.
You make it worse.
(HORN HONKING) Here's a tip for you, pal.
Thank you, Mr.
Marquez.
I didn't even carry your luggage.
Oh, I had a good week.
We celebrate when fortune smiles,
and we share the good fortune.
Remember to say nice things about us
Americans, huh?
No!
MAN: Hey, stop!
Monsieur, bonsoir.
For you, Mr. Ratchett,
the best table in the house. Just here,
sir.
The very best table.
No, I want that one. Hey, Masterman.
You got everything?
Kind of you to inquire, Mr. MacQueen.
I do not make mistakes. Oh, my goodness!
It's Count Andrenyi.
Come, come, come.
I saw you dance at the Monte Cristo.
Could I take your photograph?
(CAMERA CLICKS) (ALL EXCLAIMING)
(MEN GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS) Please, my face, no!
(CAMERA CLICKS)
(CAMERA CLATTERS)
REPORTER: Sorry.
(SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
The Simplon Orient Express... with stops
in Sofia, Niš,
Belgrade, Vinkovci, Brod...
with transfers to Bucharest, Zagreb,
Trieste, Venezia, Milan, Lausanne...
Dijon, Paris, Boulogne, Calais...
with connection to Dover and London,
leaves in fifteen minutes! BOUC: This way,
Michel!
Precious cargo.
I need a first-class compartment.
Give special care to my friend, Michel.
I want him pampered like a zoo panda.
But Monsieur Bouc, we are fully booked.
There's no space left. Then we make space.
He can have the number eleven.
The eleven is always kept open for
official use.
It's very comfortable.
Eleven is taken.
The Austrian professor booked it two days
ago.
There is not one first-class
sleeper car on the whole train?
Negative, sir.
Second-class? There's no space left at
all.
POIROT: Mademoiselle Debenham.
Mr. Poirot, are you joining us?
It depends who wins this debate.
Have all the passengers arrived? All but
one.
Mr.
Harris. BOUC: "All passengers must check
in
"at least one half hour prior to time of
departure...
"or their seat may be forfeit."
The half hour has passed. The seat is
forfeit.
Please take Monsieur Poirot's luggage
to number three with Mr. MacQueen.
POIROT: Merci, Bouc. Enjoy, my friend.
Welcome, sir.
Merci. Number three is unlucky.
(BELL RINGING)
(GASPS) Oh! Apologies, madame.
I meant no disrespect.
Well, you could try to mean a little.
(CHUCKLES)
One thing about train travel, you're
always
knocking into somebody.
It's wonderful.
Though, I am looking forward to getting
back.
Travel is fine for spicy food, mosques,
meeting men.
But eventually, you just miss your own
bed.
(MRS.
HUBBARD SIGHS) I've been accused of
husband hunting abroad.
Well, I can't, in all honesty, deny it.
I like my time alone, I do.
But a lady has certain needs that deserve
to be met
if she has any money...
and preferably, on a regular basis.
(BOTH CHUCKLE) Oh! (SHRIEKS) Oh, my!
(LAUGHS) Fire in the kitchen!
POIROT: Farewell, madame.
(CHUCKLES) COUNTESS ANDRENYI: Good
evening.
Bonsoir. Number nine.
Good evening.
Bonsoir, bonsoir.
How you doing? Bonsoir.
Oh. Excusez-moi.
No, after you.
Merci, merci.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Ah number three.
You are Mr MacQueen? Yeah.
I think you might have the wrong berth.
Uh... (SPEAKING FRENCH)
Sorry, is there a problem sir?
No, no problem.
(IN ENGLISH) The train is full. I think
that we are, how do you say...
"bunkies."
Really?
I am equally disappointed in you. This is
nice.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(GLASS CLINKING) PRINCESS DRAGOMIROFF:
Come along, darlings.
(SIGHS)
No.
No. MICHEL: This?
Why am I not yet unpacked?
CONDUCTOR:
Five minutes to departure.
Final call for passengers!
Shall we brush you?
RATCHETT: What the hell is taking them so
long?
Soon as we get out of here, have them make
up the bed. It's already arranged, Mr.
Ratchett.
No, I want the bed made. And bring my
Dictaphone.
(DOG BARKING)
Dogs on the table.
Most disgusting thing I've ever seen in my
life.
Yes, sir. I want you to get MacQueen...
and have him bring every receipt from the
Milan sale.
I want you to get it done. Yes, sir.
I want you to get it done now.
Did I say get it done now? Right away,
sir.
(PILLS RATTLING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
(TRAIN BELL RINGING) RATCHETT:
"Better watch yourself."
MASTERMAN: Your coffee, Mr.
Ratchett. Who did this?
I can't say, sir.
MASTERMAN: Good evening, Mrs. Hubbard.
MRS. HUBBARD: Hello there, Mr. Masterman.
Well, hello.
Eyes linger any longer, I'll have to
charge rent.
I'll pay.
Mmm. Have another drink.
Are you insulted?
Hmm. Disappointed.
Some men have a good look.
(CLICKS TONGUE) All they have to do is...
keep their mouth shut, and they can take
home
any prize they want.
Still, the mouth opens.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY) Is everything all right,
Mrs.
Hubbard?
You have a strong intuition, I know.
(CHUCKLES)
My second husband used to say just so.
Hold that, it was my first.
Yeah.
Brightest man I ever met.
Face like a turnip, but I loved that
turnip.
It was nice to talk.
(CLEARS THROAT) (SPEAKS FRENCH)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Good night.
(JAZZ MUSIC CONTINUES) MICHEL: (KNOCKS ON
DOOR)
Monsieur Poirot?
POIROT: Entrez, Pierre Michel.
MICHEL: Voilà.
(MACQUEEN SNORING) When you take supper...
I will move Monsieur MacQueen into
Monsieur Bouc's
compartment.
You travel first class, monsieur.
Ah, impeccable. Merci.
Bon appétit.
...and the eggs?
(EXCLAIMS)
BOUC: Good afternoon.
Ah, Mrs. Hubbard.
Good afternoon.
There we are.
Compliments of the Orient Express.
MISS DEBENHAM: Thank you, Mr. Bouc.
I am here for all of your needs.
No, thank you. I do not drink.
(WHISPERS) It does not agree with you?
Sin does not agree with me.
Vice is where the devil finds his
darlings.
We should no longer speak.
Good afternoon. (DOG BARKS) Monsieur.
How about a apéritif?
I regret I have an appointment
with the director of the train.
He was gonna leave anyway.
Please, sir. Madame, madame.
Madame, madame.
All settled in?
Ah, merci! As advertised.
And yet, the best things on the train are
not food.
(CHUCKLING) BOUC: You know
there's something about...
a tangle of strangers pressed together
for days on end, with nothing in common...
but the need to go from one place to
another...
then never to see each other again.
Boredom plus anonymity plus a...
constant, gentle rocking.
With your hobbies, you will never amount
to anything.
God, I hope so.
Hmm. Order me the fish.
Um, exchange grouper for sole,
escarole for the potato, and...
the beef sauce for the velouté.
(SPEAKS GERMAN) Garçon, that sounds
superb.
The same for me.
(WHISPERS) The Princess Dragomiroff.
You know, if I ever were to marry for
money,
I'd marry for that much money.
I brushed Dalia this morning.
No, you tortured my darling doggy.
I asked you to brush her.
BOUC: Are you still enjoying your Dickens?
POIROT: Very much, mon ami.
You know, with your books and your capers,
you are missing out on romance.
Romance never goes unpunished.
There was, uh...
There was someone once.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION) I would prefer,
in the future,
to be sat not with that man.
Like should be seated with like.
We are not alike.
Not all of us are so concerned
with the separateness of races, Professor.
It is out of respect for all kinds
that I prefer to keep them separate.
To mix your red wine and the white
would be to ruin them both.
I like a good rosé.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(LAUGHING) Hey, how you doing?
Would you mind...
if I joined you?
Dessert is an indulgence...
and I feel kinda silly and stupid
indulging alone.
I am at my happiest alone.
But...
for a small piece of your fragelité,
please join me. Oh, with pleasure.
Excuse me, another fork?
I've been trying to make your
acquaintance, Mr. Poirot.
Merci.
I never ever sat so close to fame before.
No, I tell a lie.
Once, I was on a bus with Ty Cobb. Ball
player, Detroit.
Ah.
Would you mind if I have the little curly
bit at the top?
You're an odd bird there.
You're a strange, peculiar man.
I am of an age where I know what I like
and what I do not like.
What I like, I enjoy enormously.
What I dislike, I cannot abide.
For instance, the temporary pleasantries
before what is determined to be a business
discussion.
You're fun.
All right.
I would like to offer you a job.
"The avenger of the innocent."
It's what they call you in the papers.
And you are an innocent?
I'm a businessman. I'm an art dealer.
I mean, I'm new to it.
But my beginner's luck has panned out.
Relics, antiquities. Rugs, weird.
Orientals.
I'm new to the game, so I got the amateur
eyeball.
But I got a little problem with these,
uh...
so-called appraisers.
You can't trust a one of 'em.
Some of my customers...
they buy a piece...
they find out that they're not exactly
original...
which is hardly my fault...
if a Kashan silk scarf is a fake.
Right?
Huh? C'est bon.
But I've managed to make a few enemies, is
the thing.
I got a few letters, people making
threats.
I think, most likely, it's the Italians.
I sold them a set of Oriental carpets in
Milan.
And the buyers weren't so happy with the
provenance.
And they want their money back with
interest, you know?
Italians.
A guinea's a guinea.
And then comes along the genius detective.
Me? Yes, you.
Hercules Poirot.
Hercule.
Um... Here's what I'd like to do.
I would like to hire you to watch my
back...
until I get someplace safe.
It's easy money for you.
And it's peace of mind for me, you know?
I understand. Good.
I refuse.
I'm sorry?
That's bad. Maybe I didn't make myself
clear enough.
You see, someone's out to get me.
And I know I'm not the best guy born, not
by a long shot.
And if there's a world after this one,
I will face judgment just like you.
But...
I ain't in no goddamn rush to do it.
You're holding a gun on me?
No.
Not you. On the world.
I exist in the world. Do not point a gun
at me.
How's ten thousand sound for a week? It's
a generous offer, Mr.
Ratchett. I must decline.
Fifteen thousand?
You didn't hear me. I decline.
Oh, I get it.
It's not flashy enough for the great
Hercules Poirot, huh?
No flashbulbs...
You sell fakes to gangsters.
You're suffering the consequences.
I detect criminals. I do not protect them.
So you say "no" to my dirty money.
I say "no" to you, Mr. Ratchett.
Business with the gun, right? Is that what
it was?
It is far more personal than that.
I do not like your face.
If you will excuse me.
You liked my cake, didn't you?
The cake was excellent. Have a pleasant
afternoon, Mr.
Ratchett.
(TRAIN BELL CLANGING)
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
DR. ARBUTHNOT: Thank you.
Ooh! Cold.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(GROANS)
(EXHALES)
Hmm.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
Mysweet Katherine.
My love.
(RUMBLING) (THUNDER RUMBLING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(CHUCKLING) Mr.
Dickens.
(LAUGHING) (THUNDER RUMBLING) (GLASS
SHATTERS)
(FOOTSTEPS) Mr. Ratchett?
Mr.
Ratchett? (RATCHETT SPEAKS FRENCH)
It's nothing.
(MICHEL SPEAKS FRENCH)
Very good sir.
Good night.
(SIGHS)
(BELL RINGING)
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(BELL CONTINUES RINGING)
Mrs. Hubbard?
It's always Mrs. Hubbard.
Mrs. Hubbard.
(GRUNTS)
(THUDDING) (EXCLAIMS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(YELPS) (GRUNTS)
(BRAKES SCREECHING) Did we die?
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
MICHEL: Ladies and gentlemen, the train
has been derailed.
MASTERMAN: Are you all right, Mr. Marquez?
MARQUEZ: I'm fine. Thank you.
MICHEL: You'll be safest in your cabins.
Mr.
Bouc will speak to you all...
in the morning.
Please, you will be safest in your cabins.
POIROT: Of course.
MRS.
HUBBARD: Are we gonna die?
Oh...
(SPEAKING FRENCH) MyKatherine.
(SIGHING) Mybeautiful...
Ladies and gentlemen,
I am afraid
that our train is still unable to go
anywhere.
Yeah, except down.
How long are we supposed to just sit here?
Yes, someone must be doing something. Of
course I am doing something.
I am doing nothing.
Precisely two hours and ten minutes ago,
when we did not arrive in Brod as
scheduled...
the station master will have surmised our
situation...
and already dispatched a team to excavate
the engine...
clear our path, and send us on our way.
Until then, I assure you...
we will all be made warm and fed and
comfortable.
MISS DEBENHAM: We could walk.
We could die of exposure trying.
I have a connection to make.
My boat sails day after tomorrow from
France. Without you, I'd wager.
Or me in London.
I hold you accountable for my loss of
time, Mr. Bouc.
Madam, you cannot hold me accountable for
the weather.
Of course I can. You're the one here.
And my conference in Turin?
And I was to meet at the auto factory in
Sochaux.
Yes, some things, they are in God's hands.
It is not for us to say...
if we deserve to arrive safely at our
destination...
or if, like Lucifer, we must fall.
Breakfast for you, Mr.
Ratchett.
POIROT: Ah, Bonjour, Mr.
Masterman.
(KNOCKS ON DOOR) There is a problem?
I can't say, sir.
Mr. Ratchett?
Excuse me. (SIGHS)
That is cold air.
Please bring Monsieur Bouc immediately,
and also Dr.
Arbuthnot.
(CHAIN BREAKING)
BOUC: Good God! POIROT: Touch nothing
else,
only the body.
(BOUC BREATHING HEAVILY)
BOUC: My God, this is horrible.
First the snow, now...
I'll have to meet with the police
and make some statement in some grimy
station.
POIROT: And a man has died.
BOUC: And a man has died.
DR. ARBUTHNOT: He was stabbed.
Long, straight-edged knife.
Multiple stab wounds, some shallow,
some cut clean through muscle.
POIROT: Left-hand side or right-hand side?
DR.
ARBUTHNOT: That's the thing.
It appears the killer maybe closed his
eyes and struck blind.
POIROT: Can you estimate the time of
death? DR.
ARBUTHNOT: It's hard to say with the
window open...
but my best guess is between midnight and
2:00.
MICHEL: But no one went in his compartment
then.
I sat in my seat all night. I would have
seen if someone went in.
It's impossible.
Thank you, Doctor. Please, return to the
dining car.
Michel, secure this carriage.
Poirot.
I need your help, my friend.
You have to find who did this.
Please, I implore you,
on behalf of the Orient Express.
When the police arrive,
we can present them with the case closed.
You are the only one who can save me.
Your faith touches me, mon cher.
But I must have this rest.
Well, think of it as a little beachside
puzzle.
That's nothing to your mind!
You look up the antecedents of the
passengers.
You establish their bona fides. Then you
do what you do.
You... You... You...
You sit in a chair and you eat your
cake...
and you think until the solution presents
itself.
What else are you going to do while we sit
here in the snow?
Without constant stimulation, your little
gray cells
will starve and die.
You think that is what I do? I sit in a
chair...
and I have a little piece of cake,
and then I come up with a great idea? I
don't know what you do.
I have my Dickens.
Damn your Dickens!
If we leave this to the police,
they will choose a culprit...
right or wrong, and they will hang him.
Most probably Mr.
Marquez...
for no other reason than his name is
Marquez. Or Dr.
Arbuthnot for the color of his skin.
You are the only one who can bring
justice.
Let me have a map of this coach.
Of course.
Every passport. Anything.
Interviews arranged with all of our
passengers.
Evidence, order and method, until one
culprit emerges.
I do not approve of murder, my friend.
Every day, we meet people the world could
do better without...
yet we do not kill them.
We must be better than the beasts.
So let us find this killer.
MISS DEBENHAM: What's going on?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Ladies and gentlemen, allow me to, um...
It appears that our bad luck has worsened.
That is...
A passenger has died on the train.
Monsieur Ratchett.
Looks like they got him after all.
POIROT: You assume he was killed?
No, no.
(STAMMERS) I just mean he was in perfectly
good health.
He had his enemies, that's all. POIROT:
Indeed, he did.
He was murdered.
Good God. Murder, here?
POIROT: Alas, madame.
God rest his soul.
Someone was rummaging around my cabin
in the middle of the night.
Nobody would believe me.
What is going on?
POIROT: As we are snowbound,
I have elected to take the case...
and find for my friend, Monsieur Bouc, the
criminal.
And why you?
My name is Hercule Poirot...
and I am probably the greatest detective
in the world.
I will speak to all of you in time.
For the moment...
I must recommend that you remain
in your compartments with the doors
locked.
I feel like a prisoner here.
POIROT: It is for your own safety.
If there was a murder...
then there was a murderer.
The murderer is with us...
on the train, now.
The doors between coaches were locked at
night, hmm?
MICHEL: Absolutely. Done myself.
BOUC: The train's been searched.
There's no one hiding on it or under it.
We can therefore limit our investigation
to the occupants of the Calais coach.
Bouc, you will assist me.
As the only traveler who slept in another
coach...
you are the only one who is not a suspect.
(MEN CHATTERING) BOUC: Mr.
MacQueen, is this really the time for
drinking?
My boss is dead.
I'm out of a job, and you're looking at me
like I did it.
We make no accusations.
You knew him, so from here we must glean
the essential facts.
Were you his relative?
No, his secretary.
Book his travel, order his steaks.
The man ate more steak than I've ever seen
in my entire life.
He was in antiques.
He had no qualification for it,
not the eye or the languages.
Truth is, he had no head for business,
accounting...
none of it.
I took care of everything.
How long were you in his employ?
Twenty days shy of a year.
Prohibition wasn't to my taste...
so I found myself overseas, and in debt.
I'm a lawyer by education...
not disposition.
I was downright awful at it.
You were fond of him?
I was fond of his money.
Ratchett was crude...
demanding, insulting, and most likely a
felon.
POIROT: When did you last see him?
MACQUEEN: It must have been just after
10:00.
He called me in to go over our sales in
Italy.
POIROT: Milan, the sale of forgeries?
Yeah, yeah.
He wanted to look over the accounts.
I had to translate everything...
as the contracts were in French
and he didn't speak a word.
And when we stopped at Vinkovci...
I struck up a chat with the colored
doctor, Arbuthnot.
And we had a couple of drinks, stretched
our legs.
He had some...
odd opinions about Stalin I had to turn
around.
I don't hold a man's race against him,
but I don't often take to Britishers.
When did your party end?
He left just after 2:00.
Did you know of any specific enemies
Ratchett might have had?
Gosh.
Pick a number.
POIROT: He confided he had been
threatened?
He got a couple of nasty letters. I have
them if you like.
Some, anyway.
He tore up the rest.
Threw them into the fire.
That's them.
Merci, Mr. MacQueen.
Uh, thank you.
If we have any further questions,
we will call for you again.
(CLEARS THROAT) Have you considered the
Latin man?
Marquez.
Hell of a guy.
And, well, you know, his kind...
they don't have the same distaste for
murder,
historically speaking.
You said you don't hold a man's race
against him.
I suppose...
depends on the race.
And he was doing so well. You think it's
MacQueen?
Too early to say.
I admit, I cannot see him stabbing a man
twelve times
in a frenzy.
Not sober, anyway. Who did it then?
I do not know yet. It is time we ask.
Ask who?
The victim.
POIROT: He has twelve stab wounds and, as
Arbuthnot said, they are patternless.
If the doctor is guilty...
he certainly did not let it influence
his responsibilities. BOUC: Hey, the
watch.
Stopped at 1:15.
Now that agrees with the doctor on the
time of death. POIROT: Hmm.
It is possible, yes. Certainly possible.
BOUC: I don't quite understand.
POIROT: I do not understand, myself.
I understand nothing at all.
If you look at these two wounds...
they are powerful and deep, and yet there
is little blood.
But this was a frenzied attack.
Lashing here and there.
No pattern at all, just extreme violence.
And during all this, our victim, vigorous
and anxious
and full of coffee...
merely lies still and accepts death
without struggle...
when he also has here...
the means by which he might defend
himself.
For you.
Now, let us see here.
(SNIFFS) Barbital.
The Mickey slipped.
BOUC: Drugged him so he couldn't use this.
POIROT: And later around here, a lady's
handkerchief.
An objet de luxe, handmade.
Boom, two hundred francs in Paris.
And she even has an initial, "H."
And our little friend, the pipe cleaner.
Another clue.
POIROT: Yes, a riot of clues dropped most
conveniently.
Yet only one appears, however, to be
perhaps genuine.
And maybe this ashtray provides
the accidental breadcrumb.
A charred fragment of a note.
An attempt, perhaps, to burn evidence.
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Merci, monsieur.
(SPEAKS FRENCH) (IN ENGLISH) We may borrow
your equipment, yes?
Thank you.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
Merci, merci. (IN ENGLISH) Now,
I prefer to understand...
why a clue is left rather than what the
object is.
We seek the truth from within, not
without.
In this case, however, I may welcome a
little
scientific assistance.
You will adjust the flame.
(SPEAKS FRENCH) BOUC: It's just another
one
of those nasty letters.
POIROT: (IN ENGLISH) You are mistaken, mon
ami.
This one has a secret to tell.
Look.
BOUC: "As a strong blood is on hand, you
will die."
What does this mean?
Come with me, Bouc.
Let us fill in the gaps.
This was never a beachside puzzle.
I know the dead man's real name.
It is not Ratchett, but Cassetti.
I know that name.
Then you will also know the name
Armstrong.
BOUC: The Armstrong case?
POIROT: The story shocked the world.
Two years ago...
the renowned pilot, Colonel John
Armstrong...
and his wife, Sonia, woke to find their
only child, little Daisy...
taken from her crib as she slept.
Desperate...
the Armstrongs paid the ransom.
But soon after, Daisy was found murdered
by...
BOUC: Ratchett, who was Cassetti.
POIROT: Sonia Armstrong was with child
when she received the news.
The shock sent her into premature labor.
Neither she nor her baby survived.
BOUC: How do you know this, Poirot?
Because John Armstrong told me so himself.
He wrote to me to ask me for my help.
By the time I received his letter...
it was too late.
He was found dead of a gunshot wound.
Self-inflicted.
"Daisy Armstrong's blood is on your hands.
"You will die for it."
Indeed, you did. Monsieur Poirot?
Yes, Michel.
Mrs. Hubbard wants to speak to you.
I held her as best as I could. Ah, Mrs.
Hubbard, I'm sorry to have kept you.
You have a head full of steam and a mouth
full of words. You're goddamn right, I do.
What I have been trying...
to tell you all day.
The murderer was in my compartment last
night.
I thought I'd be killed. Turns out I might
have been...
only he got Ratchett instead.
I woke up in the dark, and I knew
there was a man in my room.
You are certain it was a man?
I know what it feels like to have a man in
my bedroom.
I told your conductor, and he wouldn't
believe me.
I said, "Check the communication door
"between my room and Ratchett's.
"He must have left through there."
Sure enough, it was unbolted.
I know I locked it... after what Ratchett
said.
(SIGHS)
He made a rather overt overture.
POIROT: Have you perhaps...
heard of the Armstrong kidnapping?
You couldn't avoid it.
Morbid stuff.
POIROT: The child's murderer, Cassetti...
died last night.
Ratchett was the man.
I told you, I knew he was a rotten one.
(GASPS) You do believe me...
about the man in my room?
I'm aware you think I'm a silly woman.
But I have proof it's true.
BOUC: It is from the uniform...
of an Orient Express conductor...
but it might have fallen from Michel's
when he was in your room.
I'm not missing any.
MRS.
HUBBARD: I found it at the foot of my bed,
on the cover...
right where I slept. What do you call
that?
I call it evidence.
Thank you so much, Mrs. Hubbard.
POIROT: Have you ever been to America?
Once.
Years ago, briefly.
For what purpose?
To confirm a suspicion. Which was?
That I wouldn't like it.
I was offered a post in Boston.
Saw Boston, went straight back to London.
Is that where Ratchett was from? Boston?
I can't says I know.
It wouldn't be proper...
to ask.
Carry on.
I last saw...
Mr. Ratchett at nine o'clock.
I brought his coffee and hung up his
clothes.
(GROANING SOFTLY)
You have a toothache, I think.
I've got an extraction booked in London
this week.
Mr. Ratchett insisted on not putting it
off any longer.
He said he was tired of hearing
my suppressed groans.
This sympathetic Ratchett...
was it his usual practice to drink coffee
at night?
Not at all. But he'd been very agitated
lately.
Said he wanted to stay alert, especially
so last night.
He found a letter in his compartment.
RATCHETT: Please tell me you didn't do
this.
If I were to leave something unpleasant
on your pillow, sir...
it would not be a letter.
Coffee.
POIROT: Surely, such a...
proper and precise valet...
would never speak to his master as you
did?
Unless he knew his career was coming to a
sudden...
end.
No mere toothache, I think.
The lungs?
The thyroid.
Spread now to stomach.
Same as got my father, five years younger.
Months at best.
"Inoperable, I'm afraid," said the doctor.
And suddenly, I wasn't... afraid.
I would only do what I wanted from here
on.
I speak my mind now.
The coffee.
It appears that his cup was laced with
barbital.
You, of course, will tell me that you did
not
put it in there.
Of course I didn't.
When and from where did you procure
the coffee and the cups?
In the kitchen, sir.
I ordered it at dinner to be ready at
9:00, and so it was.
Anybody could have got a hold of it before
me.
Merci. Mr.
Masterman.
I'm sorry about the toothache.
Merci.
I love the little cakes.
So, Miss Pilar Estravados, you are a
missionary...
but you trained as a nurse
before you changed professions, yes?
I owed it to God.
You owed Him a debt?
There were...
indulgent times in my life...
when I took more than I gave.
GERHARD: Gerhard Hardman.
Professor of engineering.
It is science that will win back
for Germany her pride. Biniamino Marquez.
BOUC: Mr. Marquez.
Listen, I wanna be clear of any
association
with the crime...
so please ask me anything.
Anything. I never lie anymore.
Did you leave your compartment at all last
night?
Only once, to get an aspirin. Mrs.
Hubbard offered me something earlier.
I declined at first, but when I couldn't
rest...
I went to ask for it.
My conference is in Turin.
I am the only Austrian to present,
which means without me...
the talks will be substandard.
Then I escaped prison,
and I bribed myself into the US...
where I swore never to lie or steal again.
You see, my friends, because when people
trust you, they buy more.
The Italians are cows. The Spaniards,
sheep.
The Belgians...
I come to my room, which I share
with the unhappy English butler.
A fish. He groans a lot.
But I'm sure he saw me sleep all night
until morning.
I should say...
in case it is relevant...
there was an embarrassing moment.
When I went to see Mrs. Hubbard...
first, I opened the wrong door.
Oh, sorry.
POIROT: What time was this?
PILAR: That must have been about...
Don't be sorry.
...twenty minutes to 11:00.
POIROT: This is interesting.
As far as it is known, you are the last
person
to see Ratchett alive.
BOUC: Your business? Automobiles.
I have three showrooms.
I come to America with nothing. And now...
POIROT: If what you say is true,
Miss Debenham will confirm it.
But it is true.
I would not lie.
May it be possible that Miss Debenham
left your compartment without you
noticing? No.
I sleep very lightly.
The slightest sound and I bolt upright.
I was surprised once.
Never again.
(CHUCKLES) No, I didn't say I was a
chauffeur.
POIROT: The photographs that spilled out
of your luggage...
there was a beautiful one with a little
boy
wearing a chauffeur's hat...
visiting his papa at work.
Who did you chauffeur?
Miss Estravados, why do your hands
have the calluses of a boxer?
PILAR: I do my work in dangerous cities...
where I cannot be governed by fear.
I trained to fight.
But you do not trust your god anymore...
since your surprise?
No, in case He is busy.
God is always busy.
BOUC: It's Masterman.
A man dying is a man with nothing to lose.
Bravo, Bouc. Except for the problem of Mr.
Marquez... who has now confirmed
that his bunkmate, Masterman...
was reading in his bed at the time of
death.
If it were easy, I would not be famous.
Next.
(GROANING) Miss Debenham...
you do not mind to brace the air?
For you, we have the picnic.
While you made my roommate suffer cramped
quarters.
I see.
Choose the best location
to extract the truth from each suspect.
Put her off-balance and me, freeze.
Clever.
Will you write down your full name
and address, please?
A pale mauve, by the way.
Miss Estravados told me you asked
the color of her dressing gown.
Merci.
"Mary Hermione Debenham."
Do you ever go by Hermione?
A constant Mary, when I'm not employed as
Miss Debenham.
Left-handed.
Unusual, I know. You mustn't have
your theory fixed
if you're testing my handwriting.
What did you think of the dead man?
Uh, I can't say I did think about him.
I don't quite see the point of your
question.
Oh, forgive me, mademoiselle, my little
originalities.
Human nature is perverse in its
complexity.
To plumb it, it takes the right tools.
These are toys, not tools, Hercule.
I prefer you put them away.
The direct method? Parfait.
You knew the doctor before traveling?
Dr. Arbuthnot?
No.
But such instant attraction?
We are not in America...
Miss Debenham.
There are no laws against what you may
feel.
Nor are there laws against silence, of
which...
I hold my...
I've never been to America.
POIROT: Perhaps I may ask about some...
words I overheard?
You and the stranger, Arbuthnot, are
closer than strangers
might be.
You said... "Not now.
When we are done. Then no one can touch
us."
What did you mean?
You think I meant murder?
To a man with a hammer, every problem is a
nail.
You live crime.
You see evil every day. Not so.
I see enough crime to know
that the criminal act is the anomaly.
I believe it takes a fracture of the
soul...
to murder another human being.
I ask again, what did you mean?
As we established...
there are no laws against my silence.
Very well.
(MEN CHATTERING) POIROT: And afterwards,
Princess Dragomiroff?
After dinner, I came to bed.
God blessed me with long life, but cursed
me with a bad back
to make it miserable.
About a quarter to 1:00...
I called for Fräulein Schmidt. POIROT:
Mmm-hmm.
She massaged me...
and read to me for a while.
Then I sleep. POIROT: Mmm-hmm.
Were you ever acquainted...
with a family by the name of Armstrong?
(DOG BARKS)
They endured an unspeakable tragedy.
I was an admirer of Sonia Armstrong's
mother...
Linda Arden, the actress.
A once-a-century talent.
Miss Arden was to turn to directing.
She would have become the first
woman titan of Broadway...
were it not for the tragedy.
And this Linda Arden, she is dead?
She might as well be.
She no longer leaves her home.
(PRINCESS DRAGOMIROFF SIGHS)
Daisy was my goddaughter.
She was a...
I don't see how this relates to our
troubles, Detective.
The man killed last night, his true name
was Cassetti.
The man who murdered
little Daisy Armstrong. (SPITS)
PRINCESS DRAGOMIROFF: I see.
I admit I know this family, and now this
man is dead.
The coincidence...
must seem unbearable.
You may be permitted a coincidence.
I must now ask a few questions of your
Fräulein Schmidt.
PRINCESS DRAGOMIROFF: No. There is no
need.
I can answer to her character.
Even still, if you will allow.
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
Fraulein. Answer please in German.
But her Excellency cannot comprehend me.
That is the point.
This is yours? H for Hildegarde?
It is too fine for me.
This is the truth about last night?
As she said. She sent the conductor for
me,
then I returned to bed.
Did you see anyone when you returned?
Only the other conductor.
(IN ENGLISH) "The other conductor."
You mean Michel? (IN ENGLISH) No.
A different one than had awoken me.
Please come with me.
Are you sure you did not see him? I'm
certain.
The other conductor
was a small man with a short beard.
Fräulein, there is no other conductor.
I know what I saw. I remember because
his voice was high
and the uniform was the same exactly.
Though, I suspect, missing one button.
Sir, I need your passkey immediately.
We need to find a uniform and a red
kimono.
BOUC: Thousands of photographs,
endless pairs of socks...
dressing gowns in every color but red...
and still no contraband conductor's
uniform.
POIROT: Have we checked all the
passengers' luggage?
MICHEL: All except for the Count
and Countess Andrenyi, monsieur.
It is forbidden to search their suitcases.
BOUC: They travel under diplomatic visas.
Where else could it be?
There is one last suitcase we have not
checked.
My own.
POIROT: The killer is mocking me. Good.
His first mistake.
And as the night must follow the day...
Pardon, mademoiselle.
No, it's not mine. I told you of the
conductor.
Why would I tell you
if it was me? You would not...
which makes your compartment the ideal
choice to hide it.
Voilà, the button.
And if a conductor's uniform...
why not a conductor's passkey?
Now we know how the killer magically
passed through
locked doors.
(SNIFFS)
Bourbon. MacQueen.
Now what are we looking for now?
500 pounds.
MacQueen also had a ledger.
All his dealings with Ratchett.
Where is it, hmm?
(DOOR THUDS) BOUC: Poirot?
Bouc, keep everyone inside!
Monsieur!
Please stop!
Monsieur! (GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(BOTH GROAN)
(GRUNTS)
Monsieur!
Please stay where you are. (GROANS)
BOUC: Thank you, gentlemen.
Thank you.
So, it was MacQueen? You have your man?
Pardonnez-moi, madame.
How could he?
MACQUEEN: I didn't kill him!
POIROT: You tried to burn Ratchett's
accounts...
but they are still legible in places.
The maths do not tally...
because you have been stealing from him.
It is full of the...
(STAMMERS)
What is the English word? (STAMMERS) The
chocolat?
Fudge? Fudge!
It is full of the fudge!
You stole from him!
You thought you would be found out.
That is why you killed him!
Yeah.
Yeah, you're damn right I stole from him.
Thousands.
I knew his money wasn't honest.
What did it matter if I skimmed some off
the top?
But let me ask you a question.
Why would I slaughter my cash cow?
I didn't do it. I didn't kill him!
DR. ARBUTHNOT: He didn't.
He didn't.
I expect his alibi revolves around me,
drinking till the early hours.
Well, it's true. I saw him having whiskey,
and remarked
on the lesser quality of American liquor.
He offered me a tipple to change my mind,
then another.
We got to arguing politics.
He had some...
tomfool opinions on Stalin I had to
correct.
But the man knows his spirits.
(POIROT SIGHS)
A word, please, monsieur. You can confirm
you were
with him all night?
We smoked and spoke till nearly 2:00, yes.
Ah, such chums, him with his cigarettes,
and you...
Yes, you are the only man on the train who
smokes a pipe.
May I see your pipe and your tobacco,
please?
Of course.
And you, Dr. Arbuthnot, were traveling
from India, I believe.
Yes?
You're interviewing me now? Mmm-hmm.
Were you ever in Ratchett's compartment
before he was killed? Certainly not.
But this is one of your pipe cleaners,
n'est-ce pas?
If you found that in the dead man's cabin,
look elsewhere.
I am a doctor, sir.
I heal people. I do not hurt them.
About this, see, you must have worked
very hard to become a doctor.
Not many of your race are allowed the
opportunity.
Middlesex Medical College permits one per
class.
I had the honor in '24.
I was a sniper in my tour.
A sharpshooter.
Saved more than a few officers.
The more grateful, recognized a fair mind
with a steady hand...
and supported my education.
I take their generosity as a debt.
Did you know a Colonel Armstrong?
Might have known two or three Armstrongs.
Tommy in the 60th... Selby Armstrong...
No, I meant Colonel John Armstrong.
He had an American wife, and his child was
kidnapped and killed.
Oh.
Never came across the fellow.
When did you first meet Miss Debenham?
We met when we shared the railway convoy
car
from Kirkuk to Nissibin.
She claims otherwise, and she has made
herself
problematically suspicious.
Excusez-moi.
Mary is a lady. Leave her out of this.
I can vouch for her character.
As you vouched for MacQueen's time? You
won't listen to reason.
Never.
You are lucky.
The good doctor insists he did not let you
out of his sight.
See? There.
Couldn't have done it.
Yes, you could. Ratchett took a sleeping
draught each evening.
You could add barbital, easily access that
drug.
Do the same with one of the doctor's many
drinks...
and the chance to kill him is clear.
Why would I do any of that?
BOUC: We have established your motive.
POIROT: Perhaps I will suggest a different
one.
A different reason, a more personal
reason.
"A lawyer by education, not by
disposition."
Why did you pursue the law, I wonder?
Was it to appease a much loved,
but demanding father...
one who himself had made a great success
in the same field...
and then lost his position?
There was a renowned MacQueen, was there
not?
The district attorney for the state of New
Jersey...
responsible for the prosecution
of the Armstrong case.
They didn't have a suspect.
My dad was pressured to go after
this poor French woman...
a maid with a weak alibi, Susanne.
He hung his whole case on her.
She killed herself.
She was innocent.
By the time the evidence lead to Cassetti,
oh, he was long gone.
They tore my old man apart.
I couldn't do anything for him.
POIROT: And yet you claim
that you did not know Ratchett was
Cassetti?
No, no.
POIROT: But you found him.
No.
POIROT: You found him.
You bled him dry... No.
In order to settle your father's debts,
and then finally, to settle the score.
No, no, no. No.
It wasn't...
It wasn't like that. It's not the way...
(MRS. HUBBARD SCREAMS)
Someone kicked in the door...
BOUC: Doctor!
Covered my face.
All right, this needs to come out now. I
want my bag.
Of course.
It's in my compartment.
There will be no fingerprints.
The killer was disposing of the murder
weapon.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
It'sthere!
(WIND HOWLING) The killer didn't hit
a lung or artery.
She's lucky to be alive.
You all are.
Yeah, some genius!
Why haven't you solved this case?
You must give the man some time.
Yeah, well... I can't give that much more.
I don't have any blood left.
Yeah.
Accosting Mr.
MacQueen, and the real killer is right
here.
One of you people. I don't know who you
are.
I said nothing.
Please, leave me alone.
BOUC: (SNAPS FINGERS) Play something.
My friends, the tracks will be cleared by
morning.
Please, return to your rooms.
I'm sleeping here...
where everyone can see me and I can see
everyone.
POIROT: You should all do the same.
Conserve heat.
Remain in the open, safely in view, until
morning.
A killer will never hesitate to kill
again.
I will convey the same message to the
Andrenyis...
diplomatic immunity or not.
(THUNDER RUMBLING) POIROT: If I may,
I will look at your passports.
You know that I must talk with her.
By the way, there is a grease spot on your
wife's name.
You might want to look at that.
Elena is not well.
If you do not permit me, your reluctance
will be noted to the Yugoslav Police...
and I have no doubt that they will arrest
both you and...
(BANGS TABLE) How dare you!
Darling! (SHUSHING) Darling.
(SHUSHES)
You are funny-looking, monsieur Poirot.
Are all detectives so funny-looking?
I am sorry to wake you, Madame la
Comtesse.
COUNTESS ANDRENYI: Hmm.
I am always awake at night.
In the day, I sleep.
Some fear darkness, but I cannot stand the
light.
You are always under the influence of...
COUNTESS ANDRENYI: Barbital.
Barbital, barbital.
(CHUCKLES) I take oceans of it.
Oh, there's no use in a lie, love.
He can see right through us.
I cannot go outside without it.
I cannot sleep without it.
I take it against my fears.
What are you afraid of?
Everything.
Your passport has your maiden name as
Goldenberg.
Jewish, yes?
Not so Jewish. My middle name isn't Maria.
And you are a dancer like your husband?
No, not like my husband.
Corps de ballet.
He is touched by angels.
I have been shoved by passion and hard
work to become adequate.
(CHUCKLES)
(GLASS CLATTERS)
Excuse me, I must lie down again.
Is this your only dressing gown?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY) No, I have another.
Corn-colored chiffon.
I like speaking to detectives.
You never know what they're going to ask
you next.
I'm particularly good at capitals.
My governess was a stickler for geography.
COUNT ANDRENYI: Are you satisfied?
I am always satisfied when I uncover a
liar. Madame, your name is not Elena.
It is Helena.
Despite your clumsy attempts to change it
here
and on your luggage.
COUNTESS ANDRENYI: My husband heard
of a piece of evidence found...
a handkerchief embroidered with an "H,"
and didn't want my "H" involved.
So we changed it. The luggage and the
passport.
It's no crime to want to be distant from
trouble.
POIROT: Yet, here is trouble.
A curious detail about the Armstrong
tragedy
at the heart of this case...
is how many people were wounded by it.
The younger sister.
The actress mother...
stage name, Linda Arden.
I suppose she, too, was of Jewish
ancestry...
as who is most likely to take a stage
name?
Is it too far to suggest...
her original name was Goldenberg?
Especially when we find a young woman,
the same age...
as her surviving daughter...
living in a world of fear?
The sister of Sonia Armstrong.
(GRUNTING) Get out!
I hear noises and I run.
Just in time, yes?
You must now believe the count and
countess are the killers.
The count is protective.
The countess would no sooner kill a
bedroom spider.
And you may desist with this charade.
You are neither an Austrian, nor a German,
nor a professor.
But a good imitation.
Was it based on someone you know?
A local butcher where I grew up was a
Kraut.
Good man, great accent.
What was it?
You said "Tur-in..." the emphasis
on the wrong syllable
for a proud and proper Teuton.
"Tu-reen." You are one sharp knife,
I give you that.
Herr Professor Gerhard Hardman...
is my cover.
I'm sorry about the colored folks cracks.
Hell, I'm half a Heeb myself.
Cyrus Bethman Hardman.
You are a Pinkerton detective?
GERHARD: 30 years.
I was in Stamboul, coming back from a job,
when the office cabled.
Ratchett asked for a man to tail him,
offering triple time.
Lucky me being nearby.
(SIGHS)
He told me to look out
for a small, dark man with a high voice.
I watched that hall...
all night through a crack in my door.
Any thug...
had to go by me first.
I'll take my oath on it.
POIROT: And would you also take your
oath...
on your thirty years as a Pinkerton
Detective...
or would you lie to me again...
and deny that you were, in fact, a
policeman first?
Your gun, the checkered grip, the blue
finish...
produced for the Police Positive edition.
1927 issue.
It appears there are no end to the lies
manufactured just for me.
You can leave your gun as you go,
Professor.
(GERHARD SIGHS) From the position
of his cabin...
it would have been impossible to miss.
Unless Ratchett's door was open...
as Pilar Estravados claims she opened it.
In which case, someone could have been...
masked from his view.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
My darling Katherine. (IN ENGLISH)
This is an abominable crime...
and I am stuck, ma Katherine.
I cannot find the crack in the wall.
Why does one of them elude me?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I have always been...
so sure.
Too sure.
But now, I am very humble.
And I say, like a little child...
I do not know. I am afraid, ma Katherine.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
MICHEL: My apologies, ladies and
gentlemen.
It is not safe on board
whilst the engine is put back on the
tracks. We are to wait in the tunnel.
Thank you.
PRINCESS DRAGOMIROFF: Where are they
taking the dogs?
HILDEGARDE SCHMIDT: They'll be happy.
That's not right.
Just to stretch their legs, it's good.
No, that's not right.
MRS. HUBBARD: It's freezing!
PRINCESS DRAGOMIROFF: Are we stuck?
You asked for me?
Another interrogation?
Oh, no. I enjoy your company.
Merci, Bouc.
Uh, please.
I have a list of ten questions I am no
nearer to answering...
and the train is about to leave.
You have a clear mind... and I thought
that you might produce an insight.
Please.
MISS DEBENHAM: Hmm. "The handkerchief.
The pipe cleaner.
"The scarlet kimono. The uniform.
"The time on the watch. "Was he murdered
then?
Earlier or later?
"By one person or more?
"Which of them?"
Sorry, I can't help you.
Uh...
Merci.
Perhaps there is an eleventh question you
don't know to ask yet...
that will give you the answer to the rest.
Perhaps.
I could point an easy finger at the, uh,
Countess Andrenyi.
I discovered she was Sonia Armstrong's
sister. Are you certain?
Yes.
I suspect she may perhaps be innocent.
Perhaps.
But so many people have lied to me
on this train and do not seem to mind.
You yourself did so effortlessly.
Me?
You told me you had never been to America.
You also concealed the fact
that at the time of the tragedy...
you were living in the Armstrong
household...
as governess to their daughter.
And you know this.
I have my living to get.
A girl detained in connection to a murder
case...
no decent class family would engage me.
Miss Debenham, you planned Ratchett's
murder.
And then you sent for the countess to
witness it.
If she saw him dead, the Helena you knew
might return.
You waited for your roommate to sleep, but
she did not.
You drugged her.
But the barbital only gave her a headache.
She begged for an aspirin when the train
stopped,
when the conductor was on the station...
when the coast was clear at last...
when you were allowed to enter
Ratchett's compartment, unseen.
You loved Daisy Armstrong. You killed
Cassetti.
Cassetti was a pig.
He deserved to die.
(GUNSHOT)
(GROANS) She didn't kill him.
I did.
Mary, go.
I can't let you take the blame...
for what I did alone.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Mary, please, go. John Armstrong
was my best friend,
my commander.
He believed in me.
He sent me to medical school, gave me a
future.
Cassetti destroyed him.
In grief, I found Mary.
Then I found Ratchett.
Our plan was to reveal him to the police,
that's what you heard.
But when I saw his face...
I knew he didn't deserve a trial.
(STAMMERS) So, you drugged MacQueen.
You changed the time on the watch...
so that you could lie about the time of
death.
I couldn't let Mary be accused.
Or MacQueen.
My sins are mine to pay for, alone.
I'm a soldier.
A soldier kills to protect.
And now, Mr. Poirot,
I must protect myself from you.
(GUNSHOT)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Why aren't you dead yet?
(PANTING) Poirot?
(MEN PANTING)
POIROT: Gentlemen, stop! Sir, we need to
get
all the passengers
back on the train.
POIROT: You will retire...
away from the train...
until I tell you to return.
You tell your lies...
and you think no one will know.
But there are two people who will know.
Yes, two people.
Your God...
and Hercule Poirot.
It is time to solve this case. Dr.
Arbuthnot asked me why I was not yet dead.
He knew, of course, the answer.
A sharpshooter who does not kill at close
range?
Your shot was not a mistake. It was a
surgery.
You could not kill me because you are no
killer.
None of you are killers.
And yet, someone must be.
There are two possible solutions to this
crime.
One difficult, because it fits with most
but not all of the facts...
and one more...
complex.
The first solution.
Ratchett had enemies.
A rogue Mafioso steals onto the train at
Vinkovci...
as MacQueen and Arbuthnot take the air.
Equipped with a uniform and a passkey, he
stabs Ratchett.
He leaves through Mrs.
Hubbard's compartment,
and makes his escape.
No.
No, no, no. It doesn't work.
Why hide the uniform, hmm?
Who drugs Ratchett?
Or stabs Mrs. Hubbard?
Damn it, man!
So I ask, who stands to benefit?
This crime is the murdering of a murderer.
The benefit is, perhaps...
to the spirit, an ease of suffering.
To quiet a shouting voice
in the head that prevents sleep.
There is a murderer among us.
So...
We have Dr.
Arbuthnot, a dedicated, grateful friend to
Colonel Armstrong.
He meets and finds solace in the company
of the
governess, Mary Debenham...
who is almost like a mother to the little
girl. And so close to Mrs.
Armstrong's young sister,
Helena Goldenberg...
married to a powerful man no stranger
to rage and violence.
We travel also with Daisy's godmother...
to whom belongs...
the monogrammed handkerchief
found at the scene of the crime.
The letter "H" in the Russian alphabet,
of course, pronounced "N."
Natalia Dragomiroff. And her devoted maid
with a chef's eye?
Who was she before her current employ?
Might I suggest the Armstrongs' cook?
But we are not yet done.
The nurse in charge of Daisy...
her newfound religious zeal
born of guilt at allowing her charge... to
be abducted.
It was you, was it not...
in her room the night when Ratchett came
in
through the window?
(CLATTERING)
Did you have a glass of wine too many
with your supper that night?
Have you blamed yourself ever since...
for not being alert to stop him?
She knew nothing but kindness...
and love, until...
(STAMMERING)
until I...
(SOBBING) MASTERMAN: No need to divine
with me, sir.
I was Colonel Armstrong's batman in the
war.
And afterwards, his valet in New York.
As fine a man as God ever made.
POIROT: Would his chauffeur agree?
Was it a bank loan, secured by Armstrong,
allows him to build his automobile empire?
He's indebted for life. Who else can we
count?
What of the Pinkerton detective,
once a police officer...
assigned to the Armstrong case?
And he becomes attached to someone,
for there is another, uncelebrated victim.
You fell in love with the maid
before she was falsely accused.
You quit the police when you witnessed...
the travesty ofjustice...
when MacQueen's father insisted on her
arrest.
When she took her own life.
(CAMERAS CLICKING) No! No, no!
Susanne was so gentle.
And she fell for me.
Old and already getting grey.
I told her she could do better...
but there she was...
on time for every date.
Why else is a train...
so full in the dead of winter? Why the
inconsistent wounds?
Why the abundance of evidence? Why...?
Why the conductor?
Pierre Michel of Avignon...
who lost his sister...
the accused maid...
Susanne Michel.
Only one soul can claim to have lost
more than any of you.
The tragic Linda Arden...
mother of Sonia...
grandmother of Daisy.
Retired from the stage...
but for one final performance.
You're an awfully clever man.
A murder should have one victim.
When Ratchett kills Daisy Armstrong...
a dozen lives are broken, deformed, ended.
They demand justice!
Of all these wounded souls, we must
finally answer...
who among them is a killer? Who takes up
the knife?
The answer is...
No single one of you could have done it.
Nor any pair.
It can only have been done...
by all of you.
Together.
Even when the avalanche changes
everything...
as does the detective, plans must change.
The kimono, the uniform.
A remarkable improvisation, the doctor who
knows how to
wound without killing.
Each has their part to play.
Do it.
MRS. HUBBARD: It was my plan.
(GROANS)
I recruited them. I had Hardman
track down Cassetti.
I sent MacQueen to work for him,
and then Masterman.
MacQueen could arrange
he travel on the day
that Michel was on duty. (INAUDIBLE)
(GRUNTS)
(SOBS)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
MICHEL: Mr. Ratchett?
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
It's nothing.
MICHEL: Bien, monsieur. Good night.
POIROT: And so it is done.
For the death of the innocent.
A life for a life.
Revenge.
No one should hang for this but me.
It was my plan!
(PANTING) Tell the police it was me,
alone.
There's no life left in me anymore.
They have a chance now.
(VOICE BREAKING) Helena, I pray...
has a chance.
They can...
go live...
find some joy...
somewhere.
Let it end with me.
They're not killers.
They're good people.
They can be good again.
There was right, there was wrong.
Now there is you.
I cannot judge this.
You must decide.
You wish to go free without punishment
for your crime...
then you must only commit one more.
I will not stop you.
You can't let them kill you.
POIROT: You give my body to the lake,
and you walk away innocent at the station.
You must silence me.
Bouc can lie.
I cannot.
Do it! One of you!
COUNTESS ANDRENYI: Don't.
I already died with Daisy.
ALL: No!
(GASPS) (GUN CLICKS)
(SOBBING)
You said your role was to find justice.
What is justice here?
Sometimes, the law of man is not enough.
Where does conscience lie?
Buried with Daisy.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(INAUDIBLE) POIROT: My dear
Colonel Armstrong.
Finally, I can answer your letter...
at least with the thoughts in my head
and the feeling in my heart...
that somewhere, you can hear me.
I have now discovered
the truth of the case, and it is...
profoundly disturbing.
I have seen the fracture of the human
soul.
So many broken lives, so much pain and
anger...
giving way to the poison of deep grief...
until one crime became many.
I have always wanted to believe that man
is rational
and civilized.
My very existence depends upon this
hope...
upon order and method and the little gray
cells.
But now, perhaps, I am asked...
to listen, instead...
to my heart.
Ladies and gentlemen...
I have understood in this case that the
scales of justice...
cannot always be evenly weighed.
And I must learn, for once...
to live with the imbalance.
There are no killers here.
Only people who deserve a chance to heal.
The police have accepted my first solution
to the crime...
the lone assassin who made his escape.
I will leave the train here to conclude
formalities.
You are all free to go.
And may you find your peace with this.
May we all.
Hello. I'm looking for a Mr.
Poirot.
He's needed on a very urgent matter.
Ah. He is on holiday.
The, uh, Kassner case again?
No, sir, far worse.
I have to take him to Egypt straight away.
There's been a murder, sir, right on the
bloody Nile.
Are you the detective?
Yes.
I am the detective.
Could you please straighten your tie?
I will see you at the car.
OFFICER: Here you are, sir.
POIROT: Merci.
Allons-y.